<resources>
    <string name="app_name">NEWS</string>
    <string name="news_content">


British Foreign Secretary James Cleverly raised the issue of Income Tax department searches on BBC offices in Delhi and Mumbai in bilateral talks with External Affairs Minister (EAM) S. Jaishankar on Wednesday.

The U.K. Foreign Secretary brought up the BBC tax issue with the EAM today, a government source told The Hindu. “He was firmly told that all entities operating in India must comply fully with relevant laws and regulations, the source said.

Last week Mr. Jaishankar, in public remarks, had said the BBC documentary was a “hatchet job” and suggested that “election season” had begun in London and New York.

BBC separate entity
Mr. Cleverly confirmed in an interview with  ANI on Wednesday that he had raised the BBC raids issue during his meeting with Mr. Jaishankar and told the EAM that the BBC was independent and  separate from the British government.


British politicians, across the political spectrum, had expressed their outrage over the raids in the House of Commons last week and questioned the U.K. government on its engagement with the (Indian) government on the issue. The Tory government had strongly defended the BBC in the House of Commons.

Also read Editorial Brazen intimidation: On the tax survey on the BBC

Mr. Cleverly is here for Thursdays G20 Foreign Ministers Meeting (FMM) and the Raisina Dialogue, a conference co-hosted by the government. The U.K. Foreign Secretary also announced on Wednesday that Britain will appoint a Tech Envoy to the Indo-Pacific, with a focus on India, the U.K. Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office (FCDO) said.

India is also an emerging global leader on technology and there are immense opportunities for better collaboration between us in this sector. That is why we will be basing our first Tech Envoy to the Indo-Pacific region, to maximise the tech expertise of both countries, Mr. Cleverly said, in a statement. This is the second such appointment for the U.K.; a British tech envoy to the U.S. was appointed in 2020 and is based in San Francisco.

    </string>

<string name="car">
    Cooking gas turned dearer on Wednesday, with the State owned oil marketing corporations increasing domestic liquefied petroleum gas cylinder prices by 50 each. The commercial 19 kg LPG refill will now be more than 350 costlier.


The price of a 14.2 kg domestic cylinder for households has consequently shot up to 1,103 in Delhi 1,102.50 in Mumbai 1,118.50 in Chennai and 1,129 in Kolkata.

LPG price hike draws flak from hoteliers, homemakers and opposition parties in Bengaluru
Opposition political parties have slammed the hike, with several demanding a rollback. The move by Indian Oil, BPCL and HPCL comes amid mounting fears over rising prices across the board, with home and car loans becoming more expensive and growing uncertainties about job security, especially in the technology sector. The latest LPG price hike follows close on the heels of the end of polling in a couple of northeastern States, just ahead of the Holi festival.


Flourish logoA Flourish data visualization
The three oil marketing corporations, who together command a lions share of the LPG market, had previously increased domestic LPG prices by an identical 50 per refill in July 2022. Barring those issued LPG connections under the Ujjwala scheme meant for economically weaker families, most households in India are either ineligible for or have given up their subsidy, and thus face the heat whenever prices are hiked.


Though the oil corporations are technically empowered to revise LPG prices every month, they tend to use this power more for commercial cylinders or the bigger refills used by establishments from tea stalls to restaurants. Following the latest revision, a 19-kg LPG cylinder costs 2,119.50 in Delhi 2,071.50 in Mumbai 2,268 in Chennai and 2,221.50 in Kolkata.
</string>

    <string name="bike">
        US President Joe Biden on Friday (local time) named two Indian-Americans Revathi Advaithi, CEO of Flex, and Manish Bapna, CEO of the Natural Resources Defence Council to the Advisory Committee for Trade Policy and Negotiations.

Biden announced a team of 14 people who will be a part of the US Advisory Committee Revathi Advaithi, Manish Bapna, Timothy Michael Broas, Thomas M Conway, Erica RH Fuchs, Marlon E Kimpson, Ryan, Shonda Yvette Scott, Elizabeth Shuler, Nina SzlosbergLandis and Wendell P Weeks, read the White House press release.

Revathi Advaithi is the Chief Executive Officer of Flex, the global manufacturing partner of choice that helps a diverse customer base design and build products to improve the world.

Since assuming the role in 2019, Advaithi has been responsible for architecting the company strategic direction and leading Flex through a transformation that is defining a new era in manufacturing.

Advaithi is focused on driving technology innovation, supply chain, and responsible, sustainable manufacturing solutions across various industries and end markets.

Prior to Flex, Advaithi was President and Chief Operating Officer for the electrical sector business for Eaton, a company with over USD 20 billion in sales and 102,000 employees. She had corporate responsibility for the Europe, Middle East, and Africa regions. Previously, Advaithi was President of Eatons electrical sector, Americas, and was responsible for North, South, and Central America.

    </string>

    <string name="aero">
        Delivering a speech at the New Delhi World Book Fair, Mr. Lavrov recollected the correspondence between Leo Tolstoy and Mahatma Gandhi and called for a polycentric world order.

Ahead of Mr. Lavrovs arrival, the Russian Foreign Ministry said he would take up the suspected sabotage of the Nord Stream II gas pipeline during the regular segment of the G-20 Foreign Ministers Meeting on Thursday.

We are united by a firm commitment to building a more just and democratic polycentric world order. Moscow and New Delhi are consistent opponents of such neocolonial practices as illegitimate unilateral sanctions, threats and other types of pressure on sovereign states, Mr. Lavrov said, articulating Russia’s position against the Western sanctions that were imposed after President Vladimir Putin launched the attack on Ukraine on February 24, 2022.


We consistently stand for respect for the cultural and civilisational diversity of the modern world, for the inalienable right of peoples to independently determine their own paths of development, Mr. Lavrov said. He also met External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar soon after his arrival. He is expected to present Russias ongoing military offensive in Ukraine forcefully during the Foreign Ministers Meeting.

Ahead of his arrival, the Russian Foreign Ministry hinted that Moscows campaign in Ukraine would dominate Mr. Lavrov’s agenda in Delhi. We are set to clearly state Russias assessments of the current security, energy and food situation. We will present an unbiased factual picture of the act of terrorism the bombing of the Nord Stream gas pipeline in the EU and NATO zone of responsibility, and the illegal seizing of Russian humanitarian fertilizer shipments designated for African and other needy countries, the Foreign Ministry said in a comment about Mr Lavrovs agenda at the G20 Foreign Ministers Meeting.

Russia reiterated support for the Indian Presidency of G-20 and also said that it will work together with Indian colleagues to achieve the desired result, adding, at the same time, we will firmly defend Russias fundamental interests and an international world order based on the central role of the UN and international law.
    </string>

    <string name="heli">
        Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko, a close ally of Russia, arrived in Beijing on Tuesday for a state visit that will be watched for hints about Chinas attitude to Moscows invasion of Ukraine.

China claims neutrality in the war, but U.S. officials have warned recently that it is considering sending military assistance to Russia. Beijing has called the U.S. allegations a smear campaign, and said it is committed to promoting peace talks.

China has long had a close relationship with Lukashenko. But his trip also illustrates the depth of Beijings ties to Russian leader Vladimir Putin and his allies.

Lukashenks government has strongly backed Moscow and allowed Belarus territory to be used as a staging ground for the initial invasion of Ukraine a year ago. Russia has maintained a contingent of troops and weapons in Belarus and the two neighbors and allies conducted joint military drills.
    </string>

    <string name="apple">
        Beijing Mar 1 AP China lashed out Wednesday at a new US House committee dedicated to countering Beijing, demanding its members discard their ideological bias and zerosum Cold War mentality
The House Select Committee on the Chinese Communist Party must view China and ChinaUS relations in an objective and rational light Foreign Ministry spokesperson Mao Ning said at a daily briefing.
We demand the relevant US institutions and individuals discard their ideological bias and zero sum Cold War mentality she said. They must stop framing China as a threat by quoting disinformation, stop denigrating the Communist Party of China and stop trying to score political points at the expense of China US relations.
The committee began its work Tuesday with a prime time hearing in which its chairman called on lawmakers to act with urgency, framing the competition between the U.S. and China as an existential struggle over what life will look like in the 21st century.
Relations between the US and China have hit their lowest level in years, with both countries enacting retaliatory tariffs and trading accusations over Chinas opaque response to the COVID19 pandemic.
Chinas aggression toward Taiwan, drive to assert control over the South China Sea and the recent flight of a suspected Chinese spy balloon over the U.S. have fuelled lawmakers desire to do more to counter Beijing. Testifying to the strength of those concerns, the 365 65 vote to create the committee was bipartisan, a rarity in the deeply divided Congress.
The committees chairman, Rep. Mike Gallagher, a Republican from Wisconsin who has been a fierce critic of Beijing, said the Chinese government has found friends on Wall Street and in lobbyists in Washington who are ready to oppose the committees efforts.
Time is not on our side. Just because this Congress is divided, we cannot afford to waste the next two years lingering in legislative limbo or pandering for the press Gallagher said. We must act with a sense of urgency.
Addressing worries the new committee could stir more anti-Asian hate crimes, Gallagher said he is committed to ensuring the focus is on the Chinese Communist Party, not on the people of China.
    </string>

</resources>